(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T14:49:24.004004",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
やっ！
Yah!
are you ready ?
Are you ready?
全方向美少女
The ultimate all-angle beauty,
乱れ髪をかき出して
tossing your disheveled hair aside,
嘘と涙で割れば
with lies and tears if you split it.
世にも美しい機械人形
The most beautiful mechanical doll in the world,
女の子の出来上がり
a girl is now complete!
眉間もね、唇もさ
Eyebrows, eyes, and lips too—
好きなように味付けしな
season them however you like.
あっちまなざししなきゃ
Without passionate eyes,
千年の恋も冷めちゃうわ
even a thousand-year love will grow cold.
運命なんて生まれた日より
Destiny isn't just decided by birth,
選んだ服で決まるもの
it's shaped by the clothes you choose.
酸いも甘いも引っ含め今は
Sweet and sour all mixed together now—
きっとちゃんと愛してる
I'm sure I love you properly.
正面でみても
Whether viewed from the front,
横からみても
from the side,
下からみてもいい女で困っちゃう
or from below, you're a gorgeous girl!
ねえ、困っちゃう？
Hey, isn't it troubling?
君は全方向美少女
You're an all-angle beauty!
ねえ、困っちゃう
Hey, isn't it troubling?
嫉妬も羨みも全部愛して受け取ってよ
Accept all envy and jealousy as love.
Eyes on you every time I find out you / You're the fire or ice or sweet sweet dream
Eyes on you every time I find out you,
You're the fire or ice or sweet sweet dream.
Eyes on you every time I find out you / You're music to my eyes and sweet sweet dream
Eyes on you every time I find out you,
You're music to my eyes and sweet sweet dream.
アイラインは延ばして
Extend your eyeliner,
睫毛もね、まつ毛もさ
let your eyebrows and eyelashes reach high,
頬ペニバラ咲かせて
let roses bloom on your cheeks,
ルージュで色を付け足して
and add color with rouge.
よく人に好かれます
I'm well-liked by everyone,
身支度も分かってます
and I know how to prep myself.
ボクっこも愛嬌も
Boyish charm and cuteness too,
デワニボチをあたえます
heaven gives me both in abundance.
広告なんて一生をかけて
Advertising takes a lifetime,
一つのポイントずつ集めるもの
collecting every single point.
酸いも甘いも味わって今は
Savoring both sweet and sour now—
きっとちゃんと愛してね
make sure you love me properly!
正面でみても
Whether viewed from the front,
横からみても
from the side,
下からみてもいい女で困っちゃう
or from below, you're a gorgeous girl!
ねえ、困っちゃう
Hey, isn't it troubling?
君は全方向美少女
You're an all-angle beauty!
ねえ、困っちゃう
Hey, isn't it troubling?
嫉妬も羨みも全部愛して受け取ってよ
Accept all envy and jealousy as love.
Eyes on you every time I find out you / You're the fire or ice or sweet sweet dream
Eyes on you every time I find out you,
You're the fire or ice or sweet sweet dream.
Eyes on you every time I find out you / 君は全方向美少女
Eyes on you every time I find out you—
You're an all-angle beauty!
チート、gifted、荒業、wanted
Cheat, gifted, rough skills, wanted.
禁忌、禁じ手、明らか盲点
Taboo, forbidden move, obvious blind spot.
反則、異次元、この世の中のもんではないです
Foul, another dimension, not of this world.
無理ゲー、それ聞いてないって
Impossible game, nobody told me about that!
あー、ライバル口を揃えて
Ah, rivals all saying in unison,
うー、ライバル口を揃えて
ooh, rivals all saying in unison,
バグで、まごれ、認めねえぜって
bugged, mixed up, "I won't acknowledge it!"
マジでこれをま、全部生で？
Seriously, all of this live?
It's生身 It's生身 yeah yeah yeah yeah
It's raw, it's raw, yeah yeah yeah yeah!
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
実力を発揮し切る前に相手の方がバックれてるらしい
Before showing full strength, the opponent backed out.
上がり切るハードル very happy 明らかに断トツでピカチ
Hurdles reaching the top, very happy, clearly standing out.
相変わらずダッピしてる身に
Still shedding my skin as I live on.
チート、gifted、荒技、wanted
Cheated, gifted, rough play, wanted
禁忌、禁じ手、明らめ盲点
Taboos, forbidden moves, obvious blind spots
反則、異次元、この世の中のものではないです
Fouls, another dimension, not of this world
無理ゲー、それ聞いてないって…
Impossible game, nobody told me that...
ay ライバル口を揃えて
Ay, rivals all saying in unison
wow ライバル口を揃えて
Wow, rivals all saying in unison
バグで、まぐれ、認めねーぜっちー
By bug, by fluke, won't admit it, geez
マジで?コレおまえ…全部生身で?
Seriously? You mean... all flesh and blood?
It’s 生身 It’s 生身 yeah yeah yeah yeah
It's raw, it's raw, yeah yeah yeah yeah
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
実力を発揮し切る前に
Before fully displaying our true abilities
相手の方がバックれてくれるらしい
It seems the opponents end up bailing out
上がり切るハードル very happy
The hurdles keep rising, very happy
相変わらず脱皮してる毎日
Every day, I'm shedding my skin as usual
誰の七光りも要らないお前の ice より icy
Don't need anyone's borrowed light, icier than your ice
オレ、パッと見出せない事ばかりだけど very happy
Though it's mostly things you can't see at a glance, very happy
あ、キレてる…呆れてる周り
Ah, they're ticked... the surroundings are dumbfounded
恵まれてる家族友達
Blessed with family and friends
もう反則的立ち位置、皆オレに任せとけば良い
Already in an illegal position, just leave it all to me
教科書に無い、問題集に無い
Not in textbooks, not in workbooks
超BADな呪い listen
A super BAD curse, listen
鏡よ鏡答えてゃって
Mirror, mirror, answer me
Who’s the best? I’m the best! Oh yeah
Who's the best? I'm the best! Oh yeah
生身のまま行けるところまで
Go as far as you can with your raw self
To the next, To the 1番上
To the next, to the very top
Now singin’
Now singin'
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
To the next, To the 1番上
To the next, to the very top
eyday オレのままで居るだけで超 flex
Eyday, just staying as I am is a super flex
eyday 誰も口を挟めない
Eyday, nobody can interrupt
eyday オレのままで居るだけで超 flex
Eyday, just staying as I am is a super flex
eyday 誰も口を挟ませない
Eyday, nobody can interrupt
学歴も無い 前科も無い 余裕で
No educational background, no criminal record, with ease
この存在自体が文化財な脳味噌
This very existence is a cultural asset of a brain
高級車は買える 免許は無い 愛車
Can buy a luxury car, no license, beloved car
全国各地揺らす逸品 このベロが bling-bling
A masterpiece shaking all over the country, this tongue is bling-bling
バレットなら満タン 関西訛り 生身の言霊
Magazines fully loaded, Kansai dialect, living words
音楽 幸運 勝利の女神 今宵も三股 bang, bang
Goddess of music, fortune, victory, a three-way tonight too
漫画みたいな輩とマンガまで張り合ってしまってるマンガ
Competing with manga-like fellows even in manga
圧倒的チカラ この頭と口から
Overwhelming power, from this head and mouth
この身体 tattoo は入って無い
This body has no tattoos entered
このツラに傷も付いて無い
This face has no scars either
繰り返し和らぎしてくれるダメージが
The damage that repeatedly soothes
イカついた年輪を刻む皺
Wrinkles carving fierce tree rings
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
オレのままで blingして bangして bangするために bornして来たニッポン
Japan, born to bling and bang and bang just being myself
鏡よ鏡答えてゃって
Mirror, mirror, answer me
Who’s the best? I’m the best! Oh yeah
Who's the best? I'm the best! Oh yeah
生身のまま行けるところまで
Go as far as you can with your raw self
To the next, To the 1番上
To the next, to the very top
Now singin’
Now singin'
Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang, Bling-Bang-Bang-Born
eyday オレのままで居るだけで超 flex
Eyday, just staying as I am is a super flex
eyday 誰も口を挟めない
Eyday, nobody can interrupt
eyday オレのままで居るだけで超 flex
Eyday, just staying as I am is a super flex
eyday 誰も口を挟ませない
Eyday, nobody can interrupt
eyday オレのままで居るだけで超 flex
Eyday, just staying as I am is a super flex
eyday 誰も口を挟めない
Eyday, nobody can interrupt
eyday オレのままで居るだけで超 flex
Eyday, just staying as I am is a super flex
eyday 誰も口を挟ませない
Eyday, nobody can interrupt
実際の感情は no think
Real emotions are no think
気付かえないフリ
Pretending not to notice
絶対的な虚実と心中
Committing suicide with absolute fiction and reality
そうやって減っていく安息
That's how peace of mind decreases
傷の切り売り 脆く叫ぶ醜態
Selling off wounds piece by piece, a pathetic, fragile cry
そんなあなたにお勧め
I recommend that to you
最高級の逃避行
The highest-grade escapism
やがて甘美な罠に 釣られたものから救われる
Soon you'll be saved from being lured into sweet traps
もはや正気の沙汰では やっていけないこの娑婆じゃ
In this mundane world where you can no longer stay sane
敢えて素知らぬ顔で 身を任せるのが最適解
Surrendering yourself with a feigned ignorance is the optimal solution
言葉で飾った花束も 心を奪えば本物か
Even bouquets decorated with words, if they steal your heart, are they real?
全てが染まっていくような 事象にご招待
Inviting you to a phenomenon where everything becomes dyed
さらば
Farewell
こんな時代に迎い討った
Tailor-made for this era
見て呉れの脆弱性
With an appearance of vulnerability
本当の芝居に騙される
Fooled by genuine acting
矢鴾と煩い心臓の鼓動
Arrows and the noisy heartbeat
残機は疾うにないようになってる
Your remaining lives are long gone
擦り減る耐久性
Durability wearing down
目の前の事象を避しつつ生きるのに手一杯
With your hands full just dodging what's right in front of you
誰か、助けてね
Someone, please help me
「あなた段々眠くなる」
"You are getting sleepier and sleepier"
浅いかな催眠術
A shallow hypnosis, perhaps
頭、身体、煙に巻く
Muddling your head and body in smoke
まさか、数多欺く
No way, deceiving so many
目の前で揺るぐ硬貨
A coin swaying right before your eyes
動かなくなる彼方
The destination coming to a halt
「これでいいんだ」
"This is fine"
自分さえ騙し騙し shut down
Coaxing even yourself into a shut down
こんな時代に迎い討った 見て呉れの脆弱性
Tailor-made for this era with an appearance of vulnerability
本当の芝居に騙される 矢鴾と煩い心臓の鼓動
Fooled by genuine acting, arrows and the noisy heartbeat
残機は疾うにないようになってる 擦り減る耐久性
Remaining lives long gone, durability wearing down
目の前の事象を避しつつ生きるのに手一杯
With your hands full just dodging what's right in front of you
誰か、助けてね
Someone, please help me
「あなた段々眠くなる」
"You are getting sleepier and sleepier"
浅いかな催眠術
A shallow hypnosis, perhaps
頭、身体、煙に巻く
Muddling your head and body in smoke
まさか、数多欺く
No way, deceiving so many
目の前で揺るぐ硬貨 動かなくなる彼方
A coin swaying right before your eyes, the destination halting
「これでいいんだ」
"This is fine"
自分さえ騙し騙し shut down
Coaxing even yourself into a shut down
どんなに今日を生き抜いても 報われぬ everyday
However hard I survive today, unrewarded everyday
もう botみたいなサイクルで 惰性の瞬間を続けているのだ
Continuing moments of inertia in a bot-like cycle
運も希望もないなら 尚更しょうがないね
If there's no luck or hope, all the more reason
無い物は無いんで諦めて 余裕で勝負するのが運命
If it's not there, give up; playing with leftovers is fate
こんな時代に迎い討った 見て呉れの脆弱性
Tailor-made for this era with an appearance of vulnerability
本当の芝居に騙される 矢鴾と煩い心臓の鼓動
Fooled by genuine acting, arrows and the noisy heartbeat
賛美はもう意味ないなんて 言る店のカリスマ
Exaltation has no meaning, a charismatic storekeeper
現実を直視しすぎると 失明しちゃうんだ
If you stare at reality too much, you'll go blind
だから、適当にね
So, do it in moderation
こんな時代に迎い討った 見て呉れの脆弱性
Tailor-made for this era with an appearance of vulnerability
本当の芝居に騙される 矢鴾と煩い心臓の鼓動
Fooled by genuine acting, arrows and the noisy heartbeat
残機は疾うにないようになってる 擦り減る耐久性
Remaining lives long gone, durability wearing down
目の前の事象を避しつつ生きるのに手一杯
With your hands full just dodging what's right in front of you
誰か、助けてね
Someone, please help me
「あなた段々眠くなる」
"You are getting sleepier and sleepier"
浅いかな催眠術
A shallow hypnosis, perhaps
頭、身体、煙に巻く
Muddling your head and body in smoke
まさか、数多欺く
No way, deceiving so many
目の前で揺るぐ硬貨 動かなくなる彼方
A coin swaying right before your eyes, the destination halting
「これでいいんだ」
"This is fine"
自分さえ騙し騙し shut down
Coaxing even yourself into a shut down
はいよろこんで
Gladly!
あなた方のため
For your sake,
退屈死んで
Dying of boredom,
あなた方のため
For your sake.
できることなら
If it's possible,
できるところまで
to wherever we can go,
あと一歩踏み出して
take one more step forward.
はいよろこんで
Gladly!
あなた方のため
For your sake.
できることなら
If it's possible,
できるところまで
to wherever we can go,
あと一歩踏み出して
take one more step forward,
嫌なことも思い出して
remember the bad things too,
地獄音頭奏でろ
and play the hell dance!
踊れ
Dance!
もっと鳴らせ
Play it more!
鳴らせ 君の三から六魔
Ring your three to six demons!
踊れ
Dance!
もっと鳴らせ
Play it more!
鳴らせ 君の病気の街を
Ring your sickly town!
隠せ 笑える他人の不幸を
Hide the amusing misfortunes of others!
映せ 不気味な超人たちを
Reflect the eerie superhumans!
鳴らせ 君の三から六魔
Ring your three to six demons!
はいよろこんで
Gladly!
あなたのために
For your sake.
欠けたとこが希望
What was missing is hope.
救われたのは僕の うちのひとりで
What was saved was one of us.
あと一歩踏み出して
Take one more step forward,
嫌なことも思い出して
remember the bad things too,
鳴らせ 不気味のカナデロ
play the eerie melody!
もう一歩踏み出して
Take one more step forward,
嫌なことも思い出して
remember the bad things too,
鳴らせ 君の三から六魔
ring your three to six demons!
ドンドンどん ッツッツ どんどんどん
Don don don tsu tsu tsu don don don
踊れ
Dance!
鳴らせ 君の三から六魔
Ring your three to six demons!
隠せ笑える他人の不幸を
Hide the amusing misfortunes of others!
映せ不気味な超人たちを
Reflect the eerie superhumans!
鳴らせ 君の病気の街を
Ring your sickly town!
隠せ笑える他人の上に
Hide above others' amusing misfortunes!
映せ不気味な超人たちよ
Reflect the eerie superhumans!
鳴らせ 君の三から六魔
Ring your three to six demons!
はいよろこんで あなた方のため
Gladly, for your sake.
できることなら できるところまで
If it's possible, as far as we can go.
怠く死んで あなた方のため
Dying of boredom, for your sake.
鳴らせ 君の三から六魔
Ring your three to six demons!
ドンドンどん ッツッツ どんどんどん
Don don don tsu tsu tsu don don don
hey boogie woogie bang bang, let's go!
buddy buddy boom boom!
hoo-ah! hey, you're my, my, ma, my buddy!
be my buddy, clap, clap, clap, get up and dance!
c'mon now, choose ya, choose ya buddy!
and let's move ya, move ya body!
let's enjoy and get closer day by day!
come on, choose ya, choose ya buddy!
and let's move ya, move ya body!
la la la la la la la la, love your smiley face!
La la la la la la la, love your smiley face!
happy to meet you, my buddy buddy!
Pleased to meet you, my buddy, buddy!
boom boom, buddy, buddy, enjoy!
happy! pokedance!
Happy POKÉDANCE!
鹿のこのこのここしたんたん
Shika no ko no ko no ko koshitantan
シカ鹿 トコトコ 現れるのこのこ
Deer, trotting, appearing here and there
ツナツナ ピョクピョク 見た目はオニャノコ？
Twig and twig, bouncing, looking like a girl?
ちかごろ噂の なかなきキワモノ
Lately rumored quite the eccentric
おてまえいかが？ へなちょこ？
How's your technique? A wimp?
すごく昔から ジャパンに生息
Inhabiting Japan since ancient times
シカせんべいなら 無限にクダサイ！
Deer crackers, give 'em to me endlessly!
トナカイは仲間 カモシカはウシカ
Reindeer are friends, serows are bovines
でもでもまとめて グーテイモク
But together they're Artiodactyla
ヌーのステップで踊ろう 夜が明けるまで
Let's dance the gnu step until dawn breaks
One, Two, Three
何度だって反芻してヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Ruminating over and over, gnu gnu gnu
予測不可能な シカ色デイズ
Unpredictable deer-colored days
アバンギャルドでオーライ カオスマシマシ
Avant-garde and alright, extra chaos
いつの間にクセになってヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Before we knew it, it's addictive, gnu gnu gnu
ハチでメチャな シカ色デイズ
Wildly messy deer-colored days
破天荒バッチカモン なんでもあり
Unprecedented, bring it on, anything goes
ルールなんてなし キミの笑顔で元気満点
No rules at all, your smile gives 100% energy
もししかして運命のま、ま、my deer!
Could it be our fated... ma, ma, my deer!
心のどこかでコシタンタン
Waiting for a chance deep in our hearts
キミとなら いつまでも
With you, forever and ever
シカのこのこのこのここしたんたん
Deer, noko noko noko noko, koshitantan
何度だって反芻してヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Ruminating over and over, gnu gnu gnu
予測不可能な シカ色デイズ
Unpredictable deer-colored days
アバンギャルドでオーライ カオスマシマシ
Avant-garde and alright, extra chaos
いつの間にクセになってヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Before we knew it, it's addictive, gnu gnu gnu
ハチでメチャな シカ色デイズ
Wildly messy deer-colored days
破天荒バッチカモン なんでもあり
Unprecedented, bring it on, anything goes
ルールなんてなし キミの笑顔で元気満点
No rules at all, your smile gives 100% energy
もししかして運命のま、ま、my deer!
Could it be our fated... ma, ma, my deer!
心のどこかでコシタンタン
Waiting for a chance deep in our hearts
キミとなら いつまでも
With you, forever and ever
シカのこのこのこのここしたんたん
Deer, noko noko noko noko, koshitantan
おだてりゃイチゴロ
Flatter me and I'm a goner
イイアイガイとツワモノかもよ
Might be a good match, a formidable foe
やることなすことドタバタ騒ぎ
Whatever we do is a slapstick commotion
都合が悪けりゃテレポート！？
If things get tough, teleport!?
ようこそ シカ部
Welcome to the Deer Club
集まれ シカ友
Gather, deer friends
シカになりたけりゃ けもの道だぞ
If you want to be a deer, it's an animal trail
今ドキJKなら 時代はシカでしょ！
For modern high schoolers, deers are the era!
シカ攻め片手におフランス！？
Attacking with deer, France in one hand!?
ヌーの声が響くよ
The voice of gnus echoes around
地球を超えて どこまでも
Beyond the Earth, anywhere at all
何度だって反芻してヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Ruminating over and over, gnu gnu gnu
予測不可能な シカ色デイズ
Unpredictable deer-colored days
プリージそれって 褒めてる？
Please, is that a compliment?
テキキでいいぞ 不条理変奏
Wandering freely is fine, absurd variations
神の使いたる シカを崇めよ シカの子神の子 満満歳！
Worship the deer, envoy of god! All hail the deer and god child!
青春手 :', 捕獲もんなんて
Youthful captures and things like that
キラリ キラリ 輝いてるね
Sparkling, sparkling, shining bright
眩しすぎるなら 暗視(ナイト)どうぞ
If it's too dazzling, night vision please
何度だって反芻してヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Ruminating over and over, gnu gnu gnu
予測不可能な シカ色デイズ
Unpredictable deer-colored days
アバンギャルドでオーライ カオスマシマシ
Avant-garde and alright, extra chaos
いつの間にクセになってヌー・ヌー・ヌー
Before we knew it, it's addictive, gnu gnu gnu
ハチでメチャな シカ色デイズ
Wildly messy deer-colored days
破天荒バッチカモン なんでもあり
Unprecedented, bring it on, anything goes
ルールなんてなし キミの笑顔で元気満点
No rules at all, your smile gives 100% energy
もししかして運命のま、ま、my deer!
Could it be our fated... ma, ma, my deer!
心のどこかでコシタンタン
Waiting for a chance deep in our hearts
キミとなら いつまでも
With you, forever and ever
シカのこのこのこのここしたんたん
Deer, noko noko noko noko, koshitantan
心のどこかでコシタンタン
Waiting for a chance deep in our hearts
人類シカ化計画
Human Deerification Plan
そんなことはさせない！
I won't let you do that!
キミとなら いつまでも
With you, forever and ever
音が止まった 色が変わった
The sound stopped, the colors changed
空白だった 記憶の彼方
Beyond memories that were blank
ドラマみたいだ 鼓動が鳴った I wonder
Like a drama, my heartbeat echoed, I wonder
足跡を辿って 分かれ道で立ち止まっている
Tracing footsteps, stopping at a fork in the road
八方美人で誤魔化した 輝きは霧の向こうへ
The brilliance masked by being a pleaser went beyond the mist
ホントのこと教えて ホントの自分に出会えた時
Tell me the truth, when I met my true self
愛し愛される 未来がきっと訪れる
A future of loving and being loved will surely arrive
見つめていたい 透明なガラスのキャンバス
I want to keep gazing at the transparent glass canvas
彩ったニュアンスカラーは 淡い、甘い、曖昧
The colored nuance colors are pale, sweet, ambiguous
探していた 素直なままの君のパレットで
I want to keep searching with your honest palette
真実だけ描いていくから
Because I'll draw only the truth
I wander I wonder
重ねた色が涙で流れて 虹色になるから
Overlapping colors flow in tears to become a rainbow
見つめていたい 透明なガラスのキャンバス
I want to keep gazing at the transparent glass canvas
彩ったニュアンスカラーは 淡い、甘い、曖昧
The colored nuance colors are pale, sweet, ambiguous
探していた 素直なままの君のパレットで
I want to keep searching with your honest palette
真実だけ描いていくから
Because I'll draw only the truth
愛し愛され未来が きっと訪れる
A future of loving and being loved will surely arrive
見つめていて
Keep watching over me
音が止まった 色が変わった
The sound stopped, the colors changed
パズルみたいな 記憶の欠片
Puzzle-like fragments of memory
誰かが呼んだ 鼓動が鳴った I wonder
Someone called, my heartbeat echoed, I wonder
彩ったニュアンスカラーは 淡い 甘い 曖昧
The colored nuance colors are pale, sweet, ambiguous
探していた 素直なままの君のパレットで
I want to keep searching with your honest palette
真実だけ描いていくから
Because I'll draw only the truth
シャラララララララ...
Shalalalalalala...
I wonder I wonder
I wander, I wonder...
重ねた色が涙で流れて 虹色になるから
Overlapping colors flow in tears to become a rainbow
見つめていたい 透明なガラスのキャンバス
I want to keep gazing at the transparent glass canvas
探していた 素直なままの君のパレットで
I want to keep searching with your honest palette
色落ちしたニュアンスからは
From nuances that have lost their color,
淡い
Faint...
ああ my
Oh my,
I might
探してたんだ
I've been searching for it,
素直なままの君のパレットで
With your palette just as honest as you are,
真実だけ描いてくから
Painting only the truth from now on.
音が止まった
The sound stopped,
色が変わった
The color changed,
パズルみたいな
Like a puzzle,
記憶のかけら
Pieces of memories.
誰かが呼んだ
Someone called out,
鼓動が鳴った
My heartbeat sounded.
I wonder
もう一度さ 声を聞かせてよ
Let me hear your voice once again.
巡れないままでいる 夏の日のカレンダー
Remaining unable to turn back the calendar of that summer day.
ただ待ってさ 笑ってみせてよ
Just wait and try smiling for me.
送り先もわからない 忘れものばかりだ
With nowhere to send them, there are only forgotten things.
ココロが壊れる音が聴こえて
I hear the sound of my heart breaking,
どれだけ君を愛していたか知って
Realizing just how much I loved you,
もう二度とは増やせない 思い出を抱いて生きて
Living while holding memories I can never increase again.
デイ バイ デイ
Day by day,
どんなスピードで追いかけたら
At what speed should I chase after you
また君と巡り逢えるだろう
So that I can cross paths with you once again?
寄り添った日々 生きている意味 くれたのは君なんだよ だから
The days we leaned on each other, the meaning of living—you gave all that to me, and that's why...
いつもココロで想い続けてる
I always keep thinking of you in my heart.
まだ僕の声は聴こえている？
Can my voice still reach you?
止まらない日々 君に逢う旅
Through these unstoppable days, my journey to meet you,
よく似合う笑み浮かべて待っていて
Please wait with that familiar smile of yours.
言えなかった 胸の奥の言葉
The words deep in my heart that I couldn't say,
いまならありのままの君に渡せる
Now I can pass them to you just as they are.
囁けばさ 届けられた距離
If I whispered, the distance it could reach
ゼロセンチの指先で渡せた君になってた
Was as close as zero centimeters at your fingertips.
どうしてかな 離れている方が 言葉溢れ出すのは 今更と笑って
Why is it that the further apart we are, the more words overflow? I laugh at how late it is.
君だけに付けた いつかの流星
The shooting star I named just for you,
どんな願いを浮かべていたのかな
What kind of wish were you floating within it?
あの日君が見上げてた 藍色の先を見つめ
Gazing ahead at the indigo blue you looked up at that day.
デイ バイ デイ
Day by day,
幾億年の距離を越えて
Crossing a distance of hundreds of millions of light-years,
輝きを伝える星のように
Like a star conveying its radiance,
変わらない愛 確かなヒカリ 届くまで願い続ける だから
An unchanging love, a certain light, I will keep wishing until it reaches you, and that's why...
いつか僕ら巡り逢えたなら
If someday we are able to cross paths again,
輝きの中待ち合わせよう
Let's meet within the brilliance.
君が迷子にならないように
So that you won't become lost,
瞬きもせず照らして待っている
I will keep shining and waiting without even blinking.
消えやしない 君がくれた温もり
The warmth you gave me that will never fade,
抱きしめ僕はいまを生きていくから
I will hold onto it and live on in the present.
名前を呼ぶよ
I'll call out your name,
来る日も来る日も
Day after day, day after day.
絶えず叫ぶよ
I'll keep shouting without end.
あのままの二人でいようよ
Let's stay just the two of us, just as we were.
デイ バイ デイ
Day by day,
どんなスピードで追いかけたら
At what speed should I chase after you
また君と巡り逢えるだろう
So that I can cross paths with you once again?
分け合った日々 季節はふいに 君だけを乗せ 彼方へ
The days we shared, the seasons unexpectedly carried only you away to the far side.
だから…
And that's why...
心で思い続けてる
My heart keeps on remembering...
まだ僕の声は聞こえてる
Even now, my voice is reaching you.
かすみ目日日　目をあけるたび
With every sleepy blink, opening my eyes,
近づいていく　不器用と信じて
getting closer to a clumsy, true wish.
言えなかったんだ　胸の奥の言葉
I couldn't say it, but these words from the bottom of my heart,
今ならありのまま君に渡せる
if it's right now, I can hand them to you as they are.
どれだけ時の流れが流れても
No matter how much time flows by,
永遠に過酷茎にならないアイラブユー
I won't let it become an unchanging, harsh past.
さよーならまたいつか！
Goodbye, see you again someday!
どこから春が巡り来るのか
Where did spring come wandering in from?
知らず知らず大人になった
Before I knew it, I became an adult.
見上げた先には燕が飛んでいた
Looking up, swallows were flying by
気の無い顔で
with indifferent faces.
もしも私に翼があれば　願う度に悲しみに暮れた
If I had wings, every wish would be drowned in sorrow.
さよなら100年先でまた会いましょう　心配しないで
Goodbye, let's meet again in 100 years, don't worry.
いつの間にか花が落ちた　誰かが私に嘘をついた
Before I knew it, the flowers fell, and someone told me a lie.
土砂降りでも構わず飛んでいく　その力が欲しかった
I wanted the strength to fly through the sandstorm.
誰かと恋に落ちて　また砕けて　やがて離れ離れ
Falling in love with someone, breaking apart again, and eventually drifting away.
口の中は痰と血が滲んで　空に唾を吐く
Blood seeps from my mouth, spitting into the sky.
瞬き羽を広げ　気儘に飛べ　どこまでもゆけ
Spread your wings in a flash, fly as you please, go anywhere.
100年先も覚えているかな　知らねえけれど
Will you remember even 100 years from now? I don't know, but...
さよーならまたいつか
Goodbye, see you again someday!
しぐるるやしぐるる街へ歩み入る　そこかしこで袖触れる
Walking into the town of drizzle, brushing sleeves everywhere.
見上げた先には何も居なかった　ああ居なかった
Looking up, there was no one there—ah, no one there.
したり顔で触らないで　背中を殴りつける的外れ
Don't touch with a straight face, don't hit my back off target.
人が宣う地獄の先にこそ　私は春を見る
Beyond the hell people proclaim, I see spring.
誰かを愛したくて　でも痛くて　いつしか雨霰
Wanting to love someone, but it hurts, and eventually hail...
繋がれていた縄を握りしめて　しっかりと噛みちぎる
Gripping the rope that bound us, tearing it apart firmly.
貫き狙い定め　ケダシトラエ　どこまでもゆけ
Aim straight through, towards the tiger, go anywhere.
100年先のあなたに会いたい　消え失せるなよ
I want to meet you 100 years from now. Don't disappear!
さよーならまたいつか
Goodbye, see you again someday!
今恋に落ちて　また砕けて　離れ離れ
Falling in love now, breaking apart again, and eventually drifting away.
口の中は痰と血が滲んで　空に唾を吐く
Blood seeps from my mouth, spitting into the sky.
今羽を広げ　気儘に飛べ　どこまでもゆけ
Now spread your wings, fly as you please, go anywhere.
君を泣かすから　だから一緒には居られないな
I'm sad, so let's not be together.
君を泣かすから　早く忘れて欲しいんだ
I'm sad, so I hope you forget me soon.
人間だからね　たまには違うものも食べたいね
We're only human, after all.
君を泣かすから　そう君を泣かすから
I'm sad, yes, I'm sad.
でも味気ないんだよね
But it has no flavor, does it?
君を泣かすから だから一緒には居れないな
You make me cry, so we can't stay together.
君を泣かすから 早く忘れて欲しいんだ
You make me cry, so I want you to forget me soon.
君を泣かすから そう君を泣かすから
You make me cry, yes, you make me cry.
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような 愛してるを並べてみて
Try lining up "I love you"s as if you couldn't obtain them even after spending dozens of nights.
何十回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
As if you couldn't obtain them even after spending dozens of nights, bring me the finest full course meal.
君を泣かすから きっと一生は無理だよね
You make me cry, surely for a lifetime it's impossible.
君を泣かすから 胸がとても痛くなんだ
You make me cry, my chest hurts so much.
人間だからね たまには分かり合えなくなって
Because we're human, sometimes we fail to understand each other.
君を泣かすから また君を泣かすから
Because you make me cry, you make me cry again.
でも信じないないないんだよね 変わりたくないないないんだよね
But I have no confidence, I don't want to change.
君以外会いたくなんだよね なんて勝ってだね
I don't want to see anyone but you, how selfish of me.
大体曖昧だったよね 愛の存在証明なんて
It was mostly vague, the proof of love's existence.
君がそこにいるのね
Even though you are right there,
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような 愛してるを並べてみて
As if you couldn't obtain them even after spending hundreds of nights, try lining up "I love you"s.
何百回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
As if you couldn't obtain them after hundreds of nights, bring me the finest full course meal.
離れないでそばにいてくれたのは 結局君一人だったよね
After all, you were the only one who stayed by my side without leaving.
涙のスパイスは君の胸に残ってしまうだろうけど 残ってしまうだろうけど
Though the spice of tears will likely remain in your chest.
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような 愛してるを並べるから
As if you couldn't obtain them after thousands of nights, I will line up "I love you"s.
何千回の夜を過ごしたって得られないような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
As if you couldn't obtain them after thousands of nights, bring me the finest full course meal.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れないような 愛してるを並べるから
So you won't forget them after tens of thousands of nights, I will line up "I love you"s.
何万回の夜を過ごしたって忘れないような 最高のフルコースを頂戴
So you won't forget them after tens of thousands of nights, bring me the finest full course meal.
晴る
[Title: Haru]
貴方は風のように
Like the wind, you...
目を閉じては夕暮れ
Close your eyes in the twilight.
何を思っているんだろうか
I wonder what you're thinking.
目蓋を開いていた
With your eyelids open.
貴方の目はビードロ
Your eyes are like glass.
少しだけ晴るの匂いがした
There was a faint scent of clearing.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom.
咲いて晴るのせい
Blossom for the sake of clearing.
降り止めば雨でさえ
Even if the rain stops,
貴方を飾る晴る
It adorns you with clearing.
胸を打つ音よ響け
The sound that strikes the heart, oh resonate,
僕ら晴る風、あの雲も越えてゆけ
We are the clearing wind, go beyond those clouds.
遠く、まだ遠くまで
Far, still far away.
貴方は晴れ模様に
You, in fair weather,
目を閉じては青色
Close your eyes to the blue.
何が悲しいのだろうか
What is making you sad?
目蓋を開いている
With your eyelids open.
貴方は晴れるように
Like the wind, you...
何が悲しいのだろうか
What is making you sad?
貴方は風のように 目を閉じては夕暮れ
Like the wind, you close your eyes in the twilight,
何を思っているんだろうか 目蓋を開いていた
I wonder what you're thinking with your eyelids open.
貴方の目はビイドロ 少しだけ晴れの匂いがした
Your eyes are like glass, there was a faint scent of clearing.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴れのせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom, blossom for the sake of clearing.
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴れ
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
胸を打たず音よ出づれ 僕ら晴れ風
The sound that strikes the heart, oh calm, we are the clearing wind.
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away.
貴方は晴れ模様に 目を閉じては青色
You, in fair weather, close your eyes to the blue.
何が悲しいんだろうか 目蓋を開いている
What is making you sad with your eyelids open?
貴方の目にビイドロ 今少し雨の匂いがした
Your eyes are like glass, now there's a little scent of rain.
泣きに泣き、空よ泣き 泣いて雨のせい
Cry, oh sky, and weep, weep because of the rain.
降り頻る雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even in the frequent rain, above the clouds, it's clearing.
土を打たず音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
The sound of hitting the ground, oh resonate, we are the stormy spring.
あの海も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Crossing over that sea, far, still far away.
通り雨、草を靡かせ 羊雲、あれも春のせい
A passing shower, swaying the grass, cumulus clouds, also because of spring.
風のように、胸に春乗せ 晴れを待つ
Like the wind, carrying spring on our chests, waiting for clearing.
晴れに晴れ、空よ裂け 裂いて春のせい
Clear up, oh sky, and tear open, tear open for the sake of spring.
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴れ
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
胸を打たず音奏でで 僕ら春風
Playing the sound that strikes the heart, we are the spring breeze.
音に聞く晴れの風
Listen to the sound of the clearing wind.
さあこの歌よ出づれ
Now, this song, oh calm!
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて春のせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom, blossom for the sake of spring.
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away.
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け 咲いて晴れのせい
Clear up, oh flowers, and bloom, blossom for the sake of clearing.
降り止めば雨でさえ 貴方を飾る晴れ
Even if the rain stops, it adorns you with clearing.
胸を打たず音よ出づれ 僕ら晴れ風
The sound that strikes the heart, oh calm, we are the clearing wind.
あの雲も越えてゆけ 遠くまだ遠くまで
Go beyond those clouds, far, still far away.
貴方は晴れ模様に 目を閉じては青色
You, in fair weather, close your eyes to the blue.
何が悲しいんだろうか 目蓋を開いている
What is making you sad with your eyelids open?
貴方の目にビイドロ 今少し雨の匂いがした
Your eyes are like glass, now there's a little scent of rain.
泣きに泣き、空よ泣き 泣いて雨のせい
Cry, oh sky, and weep, weep because of the rain.
降り頻る雨でさえ 雲の上では晴る
Even in the frequent rain, above the clouds, it's clearing.
土を打たず音よ鳴れ 僕ら春荒れ
The sound of hitting the ground, oh resonate, we are the stormy spring.
何処から喰えば良いものか
From where should I bite to get something good?
美味いものか不味いものか
Is it delicious, is it unappetizing, or is it nasty?
さっぱり俺にゃ分からない
Honestly, I don't really know.
決まりばかりの世の中じゃ
It's a world of nothing but decisions.
仏が何時も水を差す 我慢するのが礼儀でしょう?
Buddha is always pouring water, acting patient is just etiquette, right?
鬼がこの身を嘲る
Demons mock this very body.
御先にどうぞご遠慮なく
Please don't hesitate to help yourself to the ancestors.
あどかっぴらげや其御口
Open wide and swallow it all down!
宴、宴が始月曜
The banquet begins at the start of the week,
勿体無いや 一度切りね
Don't waste it, take a clean cut!
好きなもの嫗食べなはれ
Eat up whatever you like!
何方を取らりゃ良いものか
What area should I plunder for something good?
白い札か黒い札か
White ticket or black ticket,
一丁賭けるとしませうか
Let's take a fifty-fifty gamble on it.
死ぬも生きるも紙一重
Death and life are separated by a hair's breadth.
御釈迦が蜘蛛の糸垂らす
Buddha lowers the spider's thread,
遥かではないわ 御出でなさい
It's not far away, please step right up.
地獄の声音が耳を打つ
The sounds of hell strike your ears,
踏み外すのも悪くない
Stepping out of bounds isn't even evil.
あど真っ盛りや此ノ宴
Fill it right to the brim at this banquet!
今宵、今宵は帰日曜
Tonight, tonight is homecoming week,
宴も酔うかよろしり
Even the banquet is dizzying and fun,
堕ちるとこまで堕ちなはれ
Fall as far down as you can fall!
あどかっぴらげや其御口
Open wide and swallow it all down!
宴、宴が始月曜
The banquet begins at the start of the week,
勿体無いや 一度切りね
Don't waste it, take a clean cut!
好きなもの嫗食べなはれ
Eat up whatever you like!
堕ちるとこまで堕ちなはれ
Fall as far down as you can fall!
落ちる どこまで 落ちなはれ
Fall, fall as far as you can down.
まわれ まわれや ひらけ ひらけや
Spin and spin, open up, open up.
赤びらけや その口
Open wide, that mouth of yours.
戯れ 戯れ絵が始まんね
The play, the play picture is beginning.
もったいないねや 一度きり
What a waste, it's only once.
好きなものだけ 食べなはれ 落ちる どこまで 落ちなはれ
Eat only what you like, fall as far as you can.
落ちる どこまで 落ちなはれ
Fall as far as you can down.
また夢から覚める 濡れた瞼を開ける
Awakening from another dream, opening wet eyelids.
狂おしいほど思い残す 遠い日の無力さを呪う
Cursing the helplessness of distant days I regret so madly.
身を焼かれるような 絶望も糧にはなろうか
Can even soul-burning despair become sustenance?
憧れに焦がれるまま 燃やし続けている
Burning away, yearning on for what I adore.
キラキラお星様宿したあなたの eyes
Your eyes harboring twinkling little stars.
カラカラ渇いて可哀想な lack of 愛?
Parched and pitiful lack of love?
全てを孤独から救う眩しい光
A dazzling light saving everything from loneliness.
僕にだけ落ちる影はあなたのせい?
Is the shadow falling only on me your fault?
致命的な欠落をくれたね
You gave me a fatal deficiency.
身勝手な巨星 狂わされた生
A selfish giant star, a life driven mad.
お願い 声を聞かせて 声を聞かせて
Please, let me hear your voice, let me hear it.
絡まって歪んでしまった傷さえ
Even the wounds that got entangled and warped—
くれたのは あなただけ あなただけ
It was you who gave them to me, only you.
あなただけ あなただけ
You alone, you alone.
お願い どっかに行っていて 僕を見ていて
Please, stay away somewhere, watch over me.
深く目に刻まれ 痛みさえ武器にして
Engraved deep in my eyes, turning even pain into a weapon.
いつかの後悔すら照らせるように
So that it can illuminate even past regrets.
あなたがいないと生きてけない
I can't live without you.
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
I'd be fine even if I sacrificed everything.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough.
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい?
What should I use to fill the void?
致命的 致命的 致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love.
運命的 運命的 運命的な"I"
Destined, destined, destined "I".
必然的 必然的 必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow.
僕を見ているね 最愛のファタール!
You're watching me, my dearest fatal!
キラキラお星様宿したあなたの eyes
Your eyes harboring twinkling little stars.
カラカラ渇いて可哀想な lack of 愛?
Parched and pitiful lack of love?
遥か彼方から放たれた美しさに 灼かれため 抉られた羽
Scorched eyes, molted feathers—
創造的堕天 あらゆる視界をジャック
by the beauty released from afar, creative fallen angel.
その輝きはエゴイスティック
Jacking every field of vision, that radiance is egotistic.
胸の奥仕舞い込んだ感情さえ引き出して昇華して
Drawing out and sublimating even the emotions locked deep inside.
あなたがいないと生きてけない
I can't live without you.
眩しさでこの身を照らして欲しい
I want you to illuminate my body with radiance.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough.
夢の中でもらうしかないのに
Even though I can only receive it in dreams.
致命的 致命的 致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love.
運命的 運命的 運命的な"I"
Destined, destined, destined "I".
必然的 必然的 必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow.
誰のものでもない 最愛のファタール!
Belonging to no one, my dearest fatal!
何度くやんだだろう
How many times have I regretted it?
何度呪っただろう
How many times have I cursed it?
どれほどの幸福を注いだとしても 満たされることのない器
No matter how much happiness is poured, a vessel never filled.
何度夢見ただろう 何度願っただろう
How many times have I dreamed, how many times have I wished?
僕の胸で疼き続けている傷を 撫でる手を
The hand caressing the wound throbbing in my chest.
この舞台で足掻くことをやめない
I won't stop struggling on this stage.
ただ一つのアイに近づきたい 固く定まったこの宿命
I want to draw closer to that single "I", this firmly set destiny.
あの星の光からこぼれた闇
Darkness spilling from the light of that star.
あなたがいないと生きてけない 何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
I can't live without you, I'd be fine sacrificing everything.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない 欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい?
Your love is still not enough, what should I use to fill the void?
しまいこむんだこの宿命 あの星の光からこぼれた闇
Locking away this destiny, darkness spilling from that star's light.
あなたがいないと生きてけない
I can't live without you.
何もかも捧げてしまってもいい
I'd be fine even if I sacrificed everything.
あなたの愛がまだ足りない
Your love is still not enough.
欠けたものは何で埋めたらいい?
What should I use to fill the void?
致命的 致命的 致命的な愛
Fatal, fatal, fatal love.
運命的 運命的 運命的な"I"
Destined, destined, destined "I".
必然的 必然的 必然的な哀
Inevitable, inevitable, inevitable sorrow.
僕を見ているね 最愛のファタール!
You're watching me, my dearest fatal!
最愛のファタール
Dearest fatal.
ドクター・キドリ です
Doctor Kidori desu
愛・爆発ってろ
Ai bakuhatte ro
簡単になれば
Kantan ni nareba
埋まった マター マター
Umatta matter matter
ドクター・キドリ です
Doctor Kidori desu
愛想いい かも
Aisou ii kamo
朧々 オオト も
Moro-oto mo
埋めた メタ メタ
Umatta meta meta
何処にもないから 寝ていたら
Doko ni mo nai kara nete itara
壊れて泣いてるユメを診断んだよ
Kowarete naiteru yume o診断(shindan)ta nda yo
時期には嘘に診あんでクルウ
Jiki ni wa uso ni shain da kurū
カオ が → 道具 に なっちゃう よ
Ka ga → nōgu ni nacchau yo
偽 が → 権力 を 取った んだ
Gī ga → kenryoku o totta nda
なくなってほしい煩悩が
Nakunatte hoshii bonnō ga
どうやら生き延びてしまった
Dōyara ikinobite shimatta
生き延びてしまった んだ !!
Ikinobite shimatta nda!!
足 が → タガメ に なっちゃう よ
Ashi ga → tagame ni nacchau yo
嘘 が → 動機 に なった んだ
Uso ga → dōki ni natta nda
疑ってほしい本能を
Utagatte hoshii honnō o
どうやら本心だと思った
Dōyara honshin da to omotta
本心だと思った んだ !!
Honshin da to omotta nda!!
クチョウ
Kuchō
ドクター・キドリ です
Doctor Kidori desu
全部やめろ よ
Zenbu yamero yo
アティチュード が
Attitude ga
感動物に届く猛毒
Kandōbutsu ni todoku mōdoku
損得の得の方だけ回った
Songokuu no toku no toku no hō dake mawatta
割った 割った 割った
Watta watta watta
カオ が → 道具 に なっちゃう よ
Ka ga → nōgu ni nacchau yo
偽 が → 権力 を 取った んだ
Gī ga → kenryoku o totta nda
なくなってほしい煩悩が
Nakunatte hoshii bonnō ga
どうやら生き延びてしまった
Dōyara ikinobite shimatta
生き延びてしまった んだ !!
Ikinobite shimatta nda!!
音 が → 機能 に なって しまう
Oto ga → kinō ni natte shimau
人 が → 偽り に 集まる
Hito ga → itsuwari ni atsumaru
塞がっ てしまえ よ 耳
Fusa kki teshimae yo mimi
どうやら届いていない診たい
Dōyara todoite inai shintai
届いていない 診たい ネ ───
Todoite inai shintai ne... ne... ne...
クチョウ
Kuchō
純情？何それ愛情？何それ
Junji? Nani sore? Aijō? Nani sore?
美味しいの？んめ美味しいのってね
Oishī no? Nme oishī no? Tene?
乱暴だめだめ感情捨て去りいせーのでぶっ飛ばすだけ
Rambō dame dame kanjō sutte sarī isē no de buttobu dake
混沌ブギウギハッピー特盛ドンビーシャイだドンビーシャイだもう
Gonton buginugi happī tokumori donbī shai da donbī shai da mō
だんだん落ちてくIQクソワロイせーので死ぬまで踊れ
Dandan ochiteku IQ kusowaro isē no de shinu made odore
完全体の山田無関心なんてありえない
Kanzen-tai no yamada mukanshin nante arienai
三千体の桑田の方がいいかな
Sanzentai no Kuwata no hō ga ii kana
わがままばかりじゃ落ち着かない冷やせがすぎて気持ち悪い
Wagamama bakari ja ochitsukanai hiyase ga sugi te kimochi warui
当たり前のことも手につかないもうなんてったらいいばっかりで
Atarimae no koto mo te ni tsukanai mō nante tたらiibakkari de
責任体力が投げ出したい狂ったように泣き出したい
Sekin-tairyoku ga nagedashitai kurutta yō ni naki dshitai
思うがまま生きて消えていきたいな
Omou ga mama ikite kienai tai na
純情？何それ愛情？何それ
Junjō? Nani sore? Aijō? Nani sore?
美味しいの？美味しいのってね？
Oishī no? Oishī no tte ne?
乱暴だめだめ感情捨て去りいせーのでぶっ飛ばすだけ
Rambō dame dame kanjō sutte sarī isē no de buttobu dake
混沌ブギウギハッピー特盛ドンビーシャイだドンビーシャイだもう
Gonton buginugi happī tokumori donbī shai da donbī shai da mō
だんだん落ちてくIQクソワロイせーので死ぬまで踊れ
Dandan ochiteku IQ kusowaro isē no de shinu made odore
ワンツーまさかり三四刈り取りもいんだってもういんだってもう
Wantsu masakari sanshi karitorimoin datte mō indatte mō
ハッピーおかわりギミーときめきいせーのでさて飛び込め
Happī okawari gīmī tokimeki isē no de sate tobikome
本能ブギウギ混沌特盛もういんだってもういんだってもう
Honnō buginugi konton tokumori mō indatte mō indatte mō
最悪ヤツらのライカ見せていせーのでぶっ飛ばすだけ
Saiaku yatsura no raika misete isē no de buttobu dake
混沌ブギウギハッピー特盛ドンビーシャイだドンビーシャイだもう
Gonton buginugi happī tokumori donbī shai da donbī shai da mō
だんだん落ちてく人生クソワロイせーので死ぬまで踊れ
Dandan ochiteku jinsei kusowaro isē no de shinu made odore
ワンツーまさかり三四刈り取りもいんだってもういんだってもう
Mantsu masakari sanshi karitorimoin datte mō indatte mō
ハッピー変わりぎみときめきいせーのでさて飛び込め
Happī kawari-gimi tokimeki isē no de sate tobikome
混沌ブギウギ簡単特盛もういんだってもういんだってもう
Gonton buginugi kantan tokumori mō indatte mō indatte mō
最悪ヤツらのライカ見せていせーのでぶっ飛ばすだけ
Saitei yatsura no raika misete isē no de buttobu dake
混沌ブギウギハッピー特盛ドンビーシャイだドンビーシャイだもう
Gonton buginugi happī tokumori donbī shai da donbī shai da mō
だんだん落ちてくIQクソワロイせーので死ぬまで踊れ
Dandan ochiteku IQ kusowaro isē no de shinu made odore
混沌ブギウギハッピー特盛ドンビーシャイだドンビーシャイだもう
Gonton buginugi happī tokumori donbī shai da donbī shai da mō
だんだん落ちてく人生クソワロイせーので死ぬまで踊れ
Dandan ochiteku jinsei kusowaro isē no de shinu made odore
もういいえ全部全部ほら忘れてしまお
Mō īe zenbu zenbu hora wasurete shimao
簡単なことじゃないが我らならできるだろう
Kantan na koto ja nai ga warera nara dekiru darō
陰にそっと隠れようがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to hide quietly in the shadows?
蕾のような花だってあんじゃない
Aren't there flowers like buds as well?
秘密にして守るのがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to keep it a secret and protect it?
誰にも邪魔されず華麗に咲いている
Blooming brilliantly without anyone getting in the way?
甘い苦にハマらない
Don't fall for the bittersweet,
その判断がくだらない
that judgment is foolish.
気になって下を向かないでいて 愛に慣れちゃいけない
Don't look down and worry, you mustn't get used to love.
無駄に飾らない 綺麗にされた花瓶も
Don't decorate needlessly, even a prettied vase
肥料も何もいらない その姿が美しい
needs no fertilizer or anything, that appearance is beautiful.
花になって ほらニヒルに笑って
Become a flower, come on, smile nihilistically,
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
that face is so thrilling I can't look away.
味見して君の毒は私の薬って 包んであげるから笑って
Taste it, your poison is my medicine, so I'll wrap you up in it, so smile.
ねえ会いたい会いたい その笑顔に
Hey, I want to see you, see that smile of yours,
会いたい会いたいって言えば笑ってくれるかな
if I say I want to see you, will you smile for me?
陰から支えるくらいはいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to just support you from the shadows?
欲を言えばこの手で咲かせてみたい
If I'm being greedy, I want to make you bloom with my own hands.
病のように心をむしばむ花 枯らしたくないの
A flower devouring the heart like a disease, I don't want it to wither.
光が届かなくとも 水を贈り続けるから
Even if light doesn't reach, I'll keep giving you water.
いい加減に気付いて 君は素敵って
Realize already, how wonderful you are,
自惚れてもっと大事に 無自覚なままで愛を蓄えて
be conceited and cherish yourself more, storing love unconsciously.
綺麗にされた花瓶も 肥料も何もいらない
Even a prettied vase needs no fertilizer or anything,
その姿で咲き誇れ
bloom proudly in that form.
花になって ほらニヒルに笑って
Become a flower, come on, smile nihilistically,
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
that face is so thrilling I can't look away.
味見して君の毒は私の薬って
Taste it, your poison is my medicine,
包んであげるから
so I'll wrap you up in it.
楽しんで君の闇は私の光って
Enjoy it, your darkness is my light,
愛してあげるから笑って
I'll love you, so smile.
陰から支えるくらいはいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to just support you from the shadows?
欲を言えばこの手で咲かせてみたい
If I'm being greedy, I want to make you bloom with my own hands.
病のように心をむしばむ花 枯らしたくないの
A flower devouring the heart like a disease, I don't want it to wither.
光が届かなくとも 水を贈り続けるから
Even if light doesn't reach, I'll keep giving you water.
いい加減に気付いて 君は素敵って
Realize already, how wonderful you are,
自惚れてもっと大事に 無自覚なままで愛を蓄えて
be conceited and cherish yourself more, storing love unconsciously.
花になって ほらニヒルに笑って
Become a flower, come on, smile nihilistically,
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
that face is so thrilling I can't look away.
味見して君の毒は私の薬って
Taste it, your poison is my medicine,
包んであげるから
so I'll wrap you up in it.
楽しんで君の闇は私の光って
Enjoy it, your darkness is my light,
愛してあげるから笑って
I'll love you, so smile.
ねえ会いたい会いたい その笑顔に
Hey, I want to see you, see that smile of yours,
会いたい会いたいって言えば笑ってくれるかな
if I say I want to see you, will you smile for me?
笑って
Smile.
つまんないデイズもう散場ね！
Boring days are already terrible!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life just wishing for miracles,
Watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
magic with no sorcery tricks mid-secret,
I wanna be free! だってまだふりだし
I wanna be free! We're still back at square one.
(The party ain't started)
Hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙迄
Hey taxi, to space for a moment.
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔物のように
Like a monster making ticking sounds and rushing the night,
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
life is magic that melts in an instant.
それなら駆け抜けて想い通り！
In that case, run through it just as you wish!
お召し馬車飛び乗ってDriving
Hop into the royal carriage and driving,
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I get a huge makeover!
我が儘のままに艶めきに注意 洒脱でDancing
Stay selfish, watch out for the allure, dancing smartly.
左様ならばご都合主義 何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス
Farewell to opportunism, someday applause and a crowd's ovation.
皆々御詠和あれ！
Everyone chant along!
(Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo-wa)
(Bibbidi-bobbidi-boowa, yeah)
混沌がっでも仕方が無い
Even if it's chaotic, it can't be helped,
ガラスシューズで踊るTonight
dancing in glass slippers tonight.
(Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo-wa)
(Bibbidi-bobbidi-boowa, yeah)
今夜に明日ないなら自由に踊った者勝ちでしょう？
If there's no tomorrow tonight, dancing freely makes you the winner, right?
(Bibbidi-bobbidi-boo-wa)
つらないデイズももう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇跡願っているだけの人生
A life just wishing for miracles
watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets
I wanna be free! だってまだ初めだし
I wanna be free! Still at the starting line
(The party ain't started)
Hey タクシー ちょっと宇宙迄
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔物のように
Like a monster, the second hand ticks loudly, urging the night
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is a magic that melts in an instant
それならば駆け抜け想定！
If so, run right through as you wish!
おしゃまな馬車飛び乗ってdrivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘のままに爛漫に注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness
洒落た街でdancin'
Dancing in a stylish city
左様なればグッバイ劣等感
If so, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, applause from the audience
皆々御詠和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
混濁がっても仕様が無い
Even if it's chaotic, there's no other way
ガラスシューズで踊るtonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょ？
So, those who dance freely win, right?
dance! ラリ ラリ ホ
Dance! La la la li ho
どんな問題も解法は一つ
Every problem has only one solution
白紙も 正解も 間違いも 愛する
Love blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes
本当のあたしの理想
My true ideal
なんだか世界は限界の気がして
The world feels like it's at its limit
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Just being safe is worrying
今すぐ jumpin' out
Jumpin' out right now
chitty chitty bang bang
chitty bang bang
唯々諾々に危機感抱く日々に
In days when I feel an urgent crisis
ぎりぎり爆発気味
Explosive feelings at the limit
たった今発散してしまおうか
Should I let it all out now?
まだまだビビビ弾巧みに乱射
Still firing away skillfully
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ
One shot is not enough
ついに導き出した君にアンサー
Finally, I found the answer for you
灰に成る迄踊って居ようよ
Dance until it turns to ash
おしゃまな馬車飛び乗ってdrivin'
Jump on the playful carriage and start drivin'
あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
I'm in the middle of a great transformation, make-up!
我儘のままに爛漫に注意
Be careful not to get caught up in selfishness
洒落た街でdancin'
Dancing in a stylish city
左様なればグッバイ劣等感
If so, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス
Someday, applause from the audience
皆々御詠和あれ！
Everyone, join in!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
混濁がっても仕様が無い
Even if it's chaotic, there's no other way
ガラスシューズで踊るtonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight
bibbidi bobbidi boowa
今夜に明日など無い
There's no tomorrow tonight
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょ？
So, those who dance freely win, right?
Happy New Year!!
あけましておめでとうございます！
Happy New Year!
今年もよろしくお願いします！
We look forward to working with you this year too!
新年一発目は… ビビデバじゃーん！
Our first song of the new year is... Bibbidiba!
Happy New Year!!
あけましておめでとう！
Happy New Year!
リーチだぞ、行くぞ！
It's our reach, let's go!
新年一発目は… 瞬間ハートビート！今年もよろしくね！
Our first song of the new year is... Shunkan Heartbeat! Best wishes this year too!
漠然とした不安 欲しかったfun
Vague anxiety, wanting fun
日常の違和感？ うんざりしていた
A sense of incongruity in daily life? I was sick of it
見慣れたありきたりな眺め
A familiar, ordinary view
理屈を超える変化を求めていた
Seeking changes beyond reason
窮屈で退屈な日々の中 突然キミは現れた
In cramped and boring days, suddenly you appeared
全身の細胞駆け巡るように 走り出した未完成なストーリー
Like racing through every cell in my body, an unfinished story started running
モノクロだった景色が今 キミと出会いカラフルに彩る
The monochrome scenery now turns colorful meeting you
brand new world
ココロ奪われた
Heart taken away
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
Fickle momentary heartbeat
揺らぐ時空の狭間
Wavering space-time interval
もうひとりじゃない 煌めく星
No longer alone, glittering star
描く未来予想図は
The future projection we draw
同じ夢を描き寄せたいよ
Wants to draw the same dream closer
果てしない 旅路 の 向こう で
Beyond the endless journey
鳴り止ま ない ロマン が 待っ て いる
An endless romance awaits
気づい た 時 に は ね
When I realized it
i can't live without you
いつまで も キミ と 一緒 なら
Forever if I'm with you
ここから 先 広がる 宇宙
The universe spreading ahead from here
晴れ渡る 空 飛び出して
Flying out into the clear sky
気分 は 上々 想像 以上
Spirits are high, beyond imagination
机上 の 空論 は 終わり に し て
Let's put an end to armchair theories
すべて 叶える 絵空事
Illusions that make everything come true
時計の針が回り回り
Clock hands spin and spin
限られた時の中で鮮やかに
Vividly within limited time
dancing time
ココロ奪われた
Heart taken away
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
Fickle momentary heartbeat
揺らぐ時空の狭間
Wavering space-time interval
もうひとりじゃない 煌めく星
No longer alone, glittering star
描く未来予想図は
The future projection we draw
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
Wants to draw the same dream closer
果てしない旅路の向こうに
Beyond the endless journey
紛れもない奇跡があるはずさ
There must be an undeniable miracle
さよならメランコリック
Goodbye melancholic
止められはしないこの衝動
This impulse cannot be stopped
突き進むだけさ
Just pushing forward
形振りかまわず are you ready ?
Without worrying about appearance, are you ready?
限界はないさ 純度無限大の異次元
No limits, infinite purity in another dimension
散らばり始めた閃き夜空染めてゆく
The scattered flashes dye the night sky
喜びは哀しみの半分かち合っていこう
Let's share joy and sorrow equally
気づいた時にはね
When I realized it
i can't live without you
いつまでもキミと一緒なら
Forever if I'm with you
ここから先広がる宇宙
The universe spreading ahead from here
晴れ渡る空飛び出して
Flying out into the clear sky
気分は上々想像以上
Spirits are high, beyond imagination
机上の空論は終わりにして
Let's put an end to armchair theories
すべて叶える絵空事
Illusions that make everything come true
時計の針が回り回り
Clock hands spin and spin
限られた時の中で鮮やかに
Vividly within limited time
dancing time
ココロ奪われた
Heart taken away
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
Fickle momentary heartbeat
揺らぐ時空の狭間
Wavering space-time interval
もうひとりじゃない 煌めく星
No longer alone, glittering star
描く未来予想図は
The future projection we draw
同じ夢を描き寄せたいよ
Wants to draw the same dream closer
果てしない 旅路 の 向こう で
Beyond the endless journey
鳴り止ま ない ロマン が 待っ て いる
An endless romance awaits
気づい た 時 に は ね
When I realized it
i can't live without you
いつまで も キミ と 一緒 なら
Forever if I'm with you
ここから 先 広がる 宇宙
The universe spreading ahead from here
晴れ渡る 空 飛び出して
Flying out into the clear sky
気分 は 上々 想像 以上
Spirits are high, beyond imagination
机上 の 空論 は 終わり に し て
Let's put an end to armchair theories
すべて 叶える 絵空事
Illusions that make everything come true
時計の針が回り回り
Clock hands spin and spin
限られた時の中で鮮やかに
Vividly within limited time
dancing time
ココロ奪われた
Heart taken away
気まぐれな瞬間ハートビート
Fickle momentary heartbeat
揺らぐ時空の狭間
Wavering space-time interval
もうひとりじゃない 煌めく星
No longer alone, glittering star
描く未来予想図は
The future projection we draw
同じ夢を引き寄せたいよ
Wants to draw the same dream closer
果てしない旅路の向こうに
Beyond the endless journey
紛れもない奇跡があるはずさ
There must be an undeniable miracle
さよならメランコリック
Goodbye melancholic
莫然とした不安 欲しかったfun
With no time to even catch my breath,
日常に違和感？ うんざりしていた
I've been running through.
さようならメランコリック
With a brand new world,
止められはしないこの衝動
our hearts were stolen away.
突き進むだけさ 形振り構わず are you ready?
A fickle, instantaneous heartbeat.
限界はないさ純度
In the narrow gap of wavering spacetime,
無限大の異次元 散りばめた閃き夜空蔓延ってく
we are no longer alone, O shining stars.
喜びは悲しみの倍分分かち合っていこう
The blueprint we draw of our future
キミとならどこまでも
will bring our dreams together.
限界はないさ 純度
There is no limit to this purity,
無限大の 異次元
infinite alternate dimensions.
散りばめた閃き
Scattered flashes of inspiration
夜空蔓延ってく
spill across the night sky.
喜びは 悲しみの倍分分かち合っていこう
Joy and sorrow will be shared twofold,
キミとならどこまでも
as long as I'm with you.
キミとなら どこまでも
No matter where we go.
波打ち際 ほどけた髪 帽子の先
At the water's edge, untied hair, the tip of a hat,
見覚えある 青いワーゲン stop the flashback
a familiar blue Volkswagen. Stop the flashback.
南風の
Southern winds,
いたずらな魔法ね
mischievous magic.
遠い夏の あの眩暈に 戻さないで again
Don't take me back to that distant summer dizziness, again.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
今だけは 寄り添ってあげるわ
Just for now, I'll snuggle up to you,
唇にくぬもり残して close to you
leaving warmth on your lips, close to you.
肩すくめて ボンネットから腰上げて
Shrugging shoulders, lifting hips from the bonnet.
語りすぎよ 飽きてきたわ
Talking too much, getting tired of it.
似た人みたい
Looking like someone else,
解けかけた魔法ね
the fading magic.
遠い夏のあの眩暈に戻したいの no more
I want to go back to that distant summer dizziness, no more.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
夕立に付き合う気 ないから stray my heart
I don't feel like sticking around for the evening shower, stray my heart.
崩れてくオンショア 波のまにまに
As the onshore crumbles, at the mercy of the waves.
maybe love, stray my heart
何もかも蜃気楼
Everything is a mirage,
夏の女神の気まぐれね
the whims of the summer goddess.
いつかまただなんて i never say
Someday, I'll never say again.
唇にうらはら残したままで
Leaving a grudge on your lips, as it is.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
今だけは 寄り添ってあげるわ
Just for now, I'll snuggle up to you,
唇にくぬもり残して close to you
leaving warmth on your lips, close to you.
肩すくめて ボンネットから腰上げて
Shrugging shoulders, lifting hips from the bonnet.
語りすぎよ 飽きてきたわ
Talking too much, getting tired of it.
似た人みたい
Looking like someone else,
解けかけた魔法ね
the fading magic.
遠い夏のあの眩暈に戻したいの no more
I want to go back to that distant summer dizziness, no more.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
夕立に付き合う気 ないから stray my heart
I don't feel like sticking around for the evening shower, stray my heart.
崩れてくオンショア 波のまにまに
As the onshore crumbles, at the mercy of the waves.
maybe love, stray my heart
何もかも蜃気楼
Everything is a mirage,
夏の女神の気まぐれね
the whims of the summer goddess.
いつかまただなんて i never say
Someday, I'll never say again.
唇にうらはら残したままで
Leaving a grudge on your lips, as it is.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
今だけは 寄り添ってあげるわ
Just for now, I'll snuggle up to you,
唇にくぬもり残して close to you
leaving warmth on your lips, close to you.
肩すくめて ボンネットから腰上げて
Shrugging shoulders, lifting hips from the bonnet.
語りすぎよ 飽きてきたわ
Talking too much, getting tired of it.
似た人みたい
Looking like someone else,
解けかけた魔法ね
the fading magic.
遠い夏のあの眩暈に戻したいの no more
I want to go back to that distant summer dizziness, no more.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
夕立に付き合う気 ないから stray my heart
I don't feel like sticking around for the evening shower, stray my heart.
崩れてくオンショア 波のまにまに
As the onshore crumbles, at the mercy of the waves.
maybe love, stray my heart
何もかも蜃気楼
Everything is a mirage,
夏の女神の気まぐれね
the whims of the summer goddess.
いつかまただなんて i never say
Someday, I'll never say again.
唇にうらはら残したままで
Leaving a grudge on your lips, as it is.
maybe love, stray my heart
さりげないしぐさして
With a casual gesture,
キスをそらすわ i go away
I'll avoid the kiss, I go away.
波打ち際 ほぐれた 髪 帽子 の 先
A hat with undone hair on the beach,
見覚え ある 青い ワージン stop the flashback
A familiar blue wagon...
南風 の in southern winds
In southern winds,
いたずら な 魔法 ね it's magic rays
It's magic rays.
遠い 夏 の あの 眩暈 に 戻さ ないで be with you
Don't return to that dazzling feeling of a distant summer,
again
(Be with you) again.
maybe love, stray my heart
何食わぬ 顔 を し て
With a nonchalant look on your face...
キス を 奪っ て don't go away
Take my kiss and don't go away,
今 だけ は 寄り添っ て あげる わ
I'll cuddle with you just for now.
唇 に 温もり 残し て close to you
Close to you, leaving warmth on your lips!
肩 すすめ て ボンネット から 腰 上げ て
I shrugged my shoulders and lifted my hips from the hood,
語り すぎ よ 飽き て き た わ stay the flashlight
I'm getting tired of talking too much,
似 た 人 みたい so look alike
So look alike,
解き かけ た 魔法 ね fade-in, fade-out
The magic is about to melt.
遠い 夏 の あの 眩暈 に 戻り たい の be with you
I want to go back to that dazzling feeling of a distant summer,
no more
maybe love, stray my heart
星 みたい に 隠れ て、合わない ピンク
Hiding like a star, a mismatched pink.
天使は、もうこの部屋にはいない
The angel is no longer in this room.
顔も知らない人と目が合う、今日この頃
Making eye contact with a stranger today.
何かを指針にして、動き始める歯車
Gears start moving with something as a guide.
私の耳を割うような音
A sound that pierces my ears,
ないものねだりで夜が明ける頃
Night falls with nothingness.
誰かの寝言が街を歩く頃
Someone's mumbling walking through the streets.
あぁ、なんて傑作だ
Ah, what a masterpiece.
help, このままじゃ、生きられない
Help, I can't survive like this.
daddy, mummy 私、いい子でいられない
Daddy, mummy, I can't be a good girl.
だから help, 強がりも度を越えちゃう
So help, my bravado crosses the line.
独りよがりな日々も悪くないでしょ？
Even selfish days aren't so bad, right?
help
流れ弾の数が増えていくから
As the number of stray bullets increases,
たまにあるラッキーじゃ、間に合わない
Occasional luck won't catch up in time.
名前も知らない人と目が合う、今日この頃
Making eye contact with a stranger today.
何かを指針にして、狂い始める歯車
Gears start going crazy with something as a guide.
夢見る時間に限りがあること
There's a limit to dreaming time.
期待した分、裏切られていく齷齪
Betrayed as much as I expected.
私じゃなくちゃいけない、理由はどこ？
I have to be myself, what's the reason?
あぁ、なんて失敗作
Ah, what a failure.
help, 大通りを歩きたい
Help, I want to walk the main street.
daddy, mummy 私、いい子で終われない
Daddy, mummy, I can't end up a good girl.
だから help, 怯懦も魔が差してしまう
So help, cowardice also lets evil in.
独りよがりなだけの優しさばかりだな
Only selfish kindness is no good, right?
help
please go away
罵詈雑言 but 宇宙の上
Scolding gossip, but above the universe,
一触即発ばっかじゃ、もう夢を見たい、けど
It's a hair-trigger situation, I want to dream again, but...
Mimpi terasa jauh, 'ku terkurung
bagai mesin 'tak berdaya, hampa, dan 'tak bernyawa
kar'na 'ku 'tak punya pilihan
help, このままじゃ、楽しくない
Help, I'm not having fun like this.
daddy, mummy 私、毛先も遊ばせたい
Daddy, mummy, I want to let my hair down.
ほらね help, 面倒なんて、全部大正解
See, help, hassle is all totally correct.
あれもこれも好き放題、私は叶えるの
This or that, do as I like, I'll make it come true.
help, このままじゃ、生きられない
Help, I can't survive like this.
daddy, mummy 私、いい子でいられない
Daddy, mummy, I can't be a good girl.
だから help, 今だけを見つめていたい
So help, I just want to gaze at the present.
そう、今だけをこぼさないように
Yes, so as not to spill the present moment.
help
help, このままじゃ歩けないんだって
Help, I can't walk like this anymore.
誰も私を必要としてないって
Nobody needs me anymore.
だから help, 今だけを見つめていたいって
So help, I just want to dwell on right now.
そう、今だけを取り逃さないように
So I don't want to let the present slip away.
help
help, このままじゃ逃げられないんだって
Help, I can't just keep running away like this.
誰も私を見てないって
Nobody even looks at me anymore.
だから help, 今だけを見つめていたいって
So help, I just want to dwell on right now.
そう、今だけを取り逃さないように
So I don't want to let the present slip away.
help
help, 大通りを歩きたい
Help, I want to walk the main street.
daddy, mummy 私、いい子で終われない
Daddy, mummy, I can't end up a good girl.
だから help, 怯懦も魔が差してしまう
So help, cowardice also lets evil in.
独りよがりなだけの優しさばかりだな
Only selfish kindness is no good, right?
help
help, このままじゃ逃げられないんだって
Help, I can't just keep running away like this.
誰も私を見てないって
Nobody even looks at me anymore.
だから help, 今だけを見つめていたいって
So help, I just want to dwell on right now.
そう、今だけを取り逃さないように
So I don't want to let the present slip away.
help
単純でめこいで混沌じゃない
It's not simple, tangled up, and chaotic.
まだ想像と妄想偏見でfine
Still, the inside and outside are prejudiced, right?
それは完全な万全の設定じゃない
It's not a complete, perfect setting.
凍ってくれないか
Won't you stay with me?
外見じゃない面倒臭さのwitch
It's not cool, a troublesome glitch.
この繊細さ敏感さ共有しよ
Let's share this sensitive sharpness.
ほら冷めきった表情は小さいちゃい
They say emotionless expressions are small, right?
見つけてくれないか
Won't you find it for me?
はいはいお家帰っちゃってこ
Hey, hey, let's go home together.
はいはい期待かせを
Hey, hey, I have high hopes.
知らないことばかり なんて 素敵だね
Not knowing anything at all is so wonderful,
これから何もかも始まってくから
because everything is about to begin from here.
Are you All Right?
何にだってなれるよ
You can become anything,
だからトライしよう
so let's try!
お遊び 鬼ごっこ かけっこ お絵描き 大縄跳び シーソー
Play, tag, footrace, drawing, jump rope, seesaw...
どこにだって行けるよ
You can go anywhere,
どきどきを抱きしめ
hugging your excitement close.
泣き虫もいじめっこも仲良く
Even crybabies and bullies get along,
こわがりでなく平気
fearless and unbothered.
女の子も男の子も
Girls and boys alike,
元気よく Go
cheerfully shout "Go!"
爆笑と涙顔 繰り返していこう
Repeating uproarious laughter and tearful faces,
ハートは柔らかいまま でいいからさ
because our hearts can stay soft.
Are You All Right?
何だって経験できるよ
You can experience anything!
全部エンジョイしよう
Let's enjoy it all,
お花見 飯盒炊さん プール 蝉取り 木の実拾い 焚き火
Cherry blossom viewing, rice cooking, pool, and more...
ぐんぐん大きくなれるよ
You can grow big and strong,
もりもりね、食べよう
eating hearty meals!
オムライス ハンバーグ おにぎり カレー 好き嫌いはなしね
Omelet rice, burger, rice balls, curry—no being picky!
体重だって想定内じゃない
Even our weight is within expected limits!
心配性ね 相談に散々ねも
You're a worrier, talking things to death,
稼いだ野望論の配信じゃない
but this isn't a stream of ambitious theories!
個人で展開大世界
Expanding a massive world individually!
知らないことばかり なんて 素敵だね
Not knowing anything at all is so wonderful,
これから何もかも始まってくから
because everything is about to begin from here.
Are you All Right?
何にだってなれるよ
You can become anything,
だからトライしよう
so let's try!
お遊び 鬼ごっこ かけっこ お絵描き 大縄跳び シーソー
Play, tag, footrace, drawing, jump rope, seesaw...
どこにだって行けるよ
You can go anywhere,
どきどきを抱きしめ
hugging your excitement close.
泣き虫もいじめっこも仲良く
Even crybabies and bullies get along,
こわがりでなく平気
fearless and unbothered.
女の子も男の子も
Girls and boys alike,
元気よく Go
cheerfully shout "Go!"
知らないことばかり なんて 素敵だね
Not knowing anything at all is so wonderful,
これから何もかも始まってくから
because everything is about to begin from here.
どこにだって行けるよ どきどきを抱きしめ
You can go anywhere, hugging your excitement close.
泣き虫もいじめっこも仲良く 平気で行こう
Crybabies and bullies get along—let's go bravely!
知らないことばかり なんて 素敵だね
Not knowing anything at all is so wonderful,
これから何もかも始まってくから
because everything is about to begin from here.
Are You All Right?
何にだってなれるよ どきどきの愛
You can become anything with thrilling love!
知らないことばかり なんて 素敵だね
Not knowing anything at all is so wonderful,
これから何もかも始まってくから
because everything is about to begin from here.
Are You All Right?
何にだってなれるよ どきどきを抱きしめ
You can become anything, hugging your excitement close.
高鳴る時代カンパイ
Cheers to this surging era!
愛ちゃん 高鳴る時代カンパイ
Ai-chan, cheers to this surging era!
what an amazing night
やたら very nice
feeling extra very nice!
ok, follow me, listen to my fluffy flow
わtわしちゃいられない 月が昇って
Can't just stay still as the moon rises,
光るネオンライト (ay) ねえ ごらん (ay) 夜が始まる (wah, wah)
glowing neon lights—hey, look, the night begins!
めえめえ 泣いていたって ツキは戻らない
Crying and bleating won't bring back the moon.
ただ落ち込み 枕にダイブ なんてナンセンス
Just getting depressed and diving into a pillow is nonsense!
夢だけで見るなんて もったいないよね？ (oh, yeah!)
Isn't it such a waste to only see it in dreams? (Oh, yeah!)
お利口さんたちが眠っている間に生まれる marvelous! (ha-ha!)
Born while the clever ones are sleeping—marvelous! (Ha-ha!)
君も目撃者になりたい でしょ？ 沈黙は “yes” と同義
You want to be a witness too, right? Silence means "yes".
make you hot 全員ハイテクノロジー 猛っているこのシーン what an amazing
Make you hot, all high-tech, this fierce scene—what an amazing...
さながら 宵の摩天楼 ふわふわ foo wha a, foo wha a, foo wha a!
Just like evening skyscrapers, fluffy, foo wha a!
退屈 クラウド な日常から 連れ出して あげましょう (foo!)
Let's take you away from the boring cloudy daily life! (Foo!)
赤さま 酔いそう なテンション ふわふわ foo wha a, foo wha a, foo wha a!
Intoxicatingly high tension, fluffy, foo wha a!
crowded (crowded!), 歌って (歌って!)
Crowded (crowded!), sing (sing!)
煙 と角に巻いて 堂々 dawn, dawn, dawn!
Wrapped in smoke and corners, proudly dawn, dawn, dawn!
まず自分 が楽しめなければ 共鳴するなんて あり得ないだから
If you don't enjoy yourself first, resonance is impossible.
喜び のお裾分け for you (woo!) ステージの上から go for broke
Sharing the joy for you (woo!), going for broke from the stage!
yippee, yippee yo, yippee yeah, yippee yo (yeah)
sheep, sheep yo, sheep yeah, sheep yo
ほら こっちだよ 華やかな世界へ おいで (oh, yeah!)
Look, it's this way, come to this gorgeous world! (Oh, yeah!)
お利口さんたちも眠っちゃいられない 巻き込むマーベラス! (ha-ha!)
Even the clever ones can't sleep, getting pulled into the marvelous! (Ha-ha!)
予測 不能 の swing magic 身体が勝手に反応し 反芻しちゃうでしょ？
Unpredictable swing magic, your body reacts and ruminates automatically!
さあ 一緒に ダンス what an amazing (ho!)
Come on, dance together, what an amazing... (Ho!)
さながら 宵の摩天楼 ふわふわ foo wha a, foo wha a, foo wha a!
Just like evening skyscrapers, fluffy, foo wha a!
退屈 クラウド な日常から 連れ出して あげましょう (foo!)
Let's take you away from the boring cloudy daily life! (Foo!)
赤さま 酔いそう なテンション ふわふわ foo wha a, foo wha a, foo wha a!
Intoxicatingly high tension, fluffy, foo wha a!
3番目の青い惑星 超BIG SIZE
The 3rd blue planet, super BIG SIZE
この広い大空の下で BEAUTIFUL LIFE
Beneath this vast sky, BEAUTIFUL LIFE
荘大な大地で WONDERFUL TIME
On this grand earth, WONDERFUL TIME
風に乗って何処まででも FEEL SO NICE
Riding the wind anywhere, FEEL SO NICE
目前の景色をふと眺め
Suddenly gazing at the scenery before me,
山へ気を取られるのは何故?
Why am I drawn to the mountains?
時は流れ 心の中で
Time flows, and within my heart
溜まるストレスが我を忘れ
Accumulated stress makes me lose myself,
俯き足早に走る日々
Running with quick steps and a bowed head daily,
近くの景色も見えない日々
Days where I can't even see nearby scenery.
たまのリフレッシュそれが大事!
An occasional refresh is so important!
山の向こうに見えるHappy
Happy seen beyond the mountains,
笑い方忘れていませんか?
Have you forgotten how to smile?
暗い顔で立ち止まっていませんか?
Are you standing still with a gloomy face?
何かに追われる事もあり
Sometimes chased by things,
また時間が迫って来たり
And time pressing in on us once more.
そんな時は大空見上げて
At times like that, look up at the vast sky,
向かい風を手で掻き分け
Parting the headwind with your hands,
この大地に立って感じれば
Standing on this earth and feeling it,
お固い事なんてお構いなし!!!
Forget being rigid and uptight!
3番目の青い惑星 超BIG SIZE
The 3rd blue planet, super BIG SIZE,
この広い大空の下で BEAUTIFUL LIFE
Beneath this vast sky, BEAUTIFUL LIFE.
危険の海身を躱し島へ架かる
Swerve past dangerous seas and span out to the island
世界変える未来島のラボへようこそ
Welcome to the lab on Future Island that changes the world
最高の夏の叶えよう野望
Let's fulfill our ambitions for the ultimate summer
未来のお宝探しちゃおう
Let's search for future treasures!
天才が奇跡を起こすはずの奇跡
A miracle where geniuses make miracles happen
脳内 手を離せない夢のファンタジー
A dream fantasy in the brain you can't let go of
常識ひっくり返すテクノロジー
Technology that turns common sense upside down
叶えちゃおう LABORATORY
Let's make it happen, LABORATORY
飾られるスウェージンピタゴラス
Adorning Schrödinger and Pythagoras
悟らす夜空の人のサテライト
Satellites in the night sky teaching us the truth
湧き出るアイデア止まらない
Bubbling ideas never stop
忙しすぎて猫の手も借りたい
So busy I'd even borrow a cat's paw
海も波も越えていく海賊を
Pirates crossing oceans and waves
常識変えていく発明を
Inventions changing common sense
そんな奴らに憧れてきた
Admiring guys like that
次は誰かが顔になる
Next, someone will become the face
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
ひらめきを巻き起こせ
Stir up inspiration
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
ひらめきを巻き起こせ
Stir up inspiration
囲む世界も飛び越して
Jump over the surrounding world too
VEGAPUNK 生み出すよアイデア
VEGAPUNK, generating ideas
VEGAPUNK 革命をここから
VEGAPUNK, revolution from here
危険の海身を躱し島へ架かる
Swerve past dangerous seas and span out to the island
世界変える未来島のラボへようこそ
Welcome to the lab on Future Island that changes the world
This mind is undefeated until my goal's completed
Let's keep on searching for the treasure yet to come
天才が奇跡を起こすはずの奇跡
A miracle where geniuses make miracles happen
脳内 手を離せない夢のファンタジー
A dream fantasy in the brain you can't let go of
常識ひっくり返すテクノロジー
Technology that turns common sense upside down
叶えちゃおう LABORATORY
Let's make it happen, LABORATORY
Twisted into evils into contents of mine
Ryders and knowledge, grading violence, six-style lights
Ideas can't stop rushing, I'm so thinking they might
Cook you out, I'm busy working into the night
The pirate king who breaks the ocean while in search of a lis-ten
A ruler of invention that can modify a reason
Last one to challenge, and something I'm gonna be
Next on the phone, I don't know what I'm gonna do
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
ひらめきを巻き起こせ
Stir up inspiration
無限の夢 未来の知恵
Infinite dreams, future wisdom
ひらめきを巻き起こせ
Stir up inspiration
囲む世界も飛び越して
Jump over the surrounding world too
VEGAPUNK 生み出すよアイデア
VEGAPUNK, generating ideas
VEGAPUNK 革命をここから
VEGAPUNK, revolution from here
言うこと聞かなきゃ振りかざす正義
Justice wielded if you don't listen
世界守る軍団の正義
The justice of the army protecting the world
秘密巡る怪しい企らみ
Suspicious schemes surrounding secrets
心の記憶に隠された狂気
Madness hidden in the memories of the heart
真実暴く危険な武器
Dangerous weapons exposing the truth
謎ね 満ち足りその夢のエネルギー
Riddle, fill that dream energy
天才が魅せる世界のカタチ
The shape of the world shown by geniuses
どこへ向かう未来の島エッグヘッド
Where is the future island Egghead heading?
はーい 注目
Hey, attention
まあ いっちょ 踊って こう か ?
Well, shall we dance a bit?
視線 牛耳って ん の は …
Who's controlling the gaze...?
i i i
赤く 火照る face
Red, flushed face
ヒートアップ しちって light up the place
Heat up and light up the place
潤い た 喉 潤 す オアシス さ マリンブルー
An oasis moistening a thirsty throat, Marine Blue
あの涙が 今の僕らを 繋げ て
Those tears connect us now, right here,
この 心 に 君 の カケラ が いる から
because a piece of you is in my heart.
一人 じゃ ない から
We are not alone.
いつか 描い た 文字 の 中 目 を 閉し た 先 に 色づく 景色 が 揺れ た
The colors in the scenery blur behind closed eyes...
少し 戸惑う 風 の 中
Amidst the slightly hesitant wind...
重なる 花びら 私たちの 声
Our voices echo as overlapping flower petals.
一瞬 一瞬 一瞬 一瞬
Every single moment, moment...
捕まえる みたい に
Like we're about to capture it,
もっと もっと もっと 踏み出せ たら
more and more, if we take that step forward—we are one.
あの 涙 が 今 の 僕ら を 繋げ て
Those tears connect us now, right here,
この 心 に 君 の カケラ が いる から
because a piece of you is in my heart.
強く なく て も いい
It's okay not to be strong.
今 の 光 を 僕 と 集め 空 に 放つ
Let's gather the light with you and release it to the sky.
この 奇跡 を 僕ら で そっと 輝かせる から
We will gently make this miracle shine with our own hands,
力 が 湧く から
because strength wells up inside.
新たな 種 を 握りしめ
Clasping a brand new seed,
遠い 未来 へ と 強く 願い 込め 撒いた
I scattered it with earnest wishes for a distant future.
希望 の 風 を 吹か せ て は
Letting the winds of hope blow through—
理想 の 花びら 祈る 明日 の 空
ideal flower petals praying for tomorrow's skies.
何百何億も
Hundreds of millions...
光る 星 みたい に
like shining stars,
ずーっと ずーっと ずーっと 終わら ない から
it will go on forever and ever without end.
この 笑顔 が 過去 を 強く 抱きしめ て
This smile embraces the past with strength,
今 未来 に この 手 伸ばし て ゆく から
and I'll keep reaching out to the future now.
時 に 転ん で も それ で いい
Even if we stumble sometimes, that's fine—
空 を 見上げよ う
let's look up at the sky.
笑い合っ た 日々 を 刻ん で ゆく
Marking down all the days we laughed and cried,
次 の 夢 を 掴み取る って 約束 する から
I promise to seize the next dream—
踏み出そ う ここ から
let's take that step forward from right here.
同じ 未来 を 見 てい たい
We want to see the same future.
あの 夢 手 に し たい
We want to make that dream ours.
触れ た 奇跡 の 中 で
Amidst this touched miracle,
その 先 まで 続く 空 に まぎれ たら
if we get swept away into the sky beyond,
君 の 場所 と 今 を 繋げ たく て
I want to connect your place and the present.
あの 涙 が 今 の 僕らを 繋げ て
Those tears connect us now, right here,
この 心 に 君 の カケラ が いる から
because a piece of you is in my heart.
強く なく て も いい
It's okay not to be strong.
今 の 光 を 僕 と 集め 空 に 放つ
Let's gather the light with you and release it to the sky.
この 奇跡 を 僕ら で そっと 輝かせる から
We will gently make this miracle shine with our own hands,
咲かせよう ここ から 一緒 に
let's make it bloom right here together,
一人 じゃ ない から
because we are not alone.
ホロライブ オフィシャルカードゲーム
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME
ステージに立つ 個性あふれるホロメンたちが織りなすわ
Unique holomembers taking the stage weave together...
無限の可能性を秘めた 多彩なコラボレーション！
A diverse collaboration holding infinite possibilities!
そこに新たな色が交わる時 心を引き付けるいつつの迷宮が響き渡る
When new colors intersect, five labyrinths that capture the heart will echo.
さあ、君も私たちと一緒に色彩あふれるステージへ！
Now, come with us to a stage full of color!
ブースターパック クインテットスペクトラム 12月20日（金）発売！！
Booster Pack "Quintet Spectrum" releasing Friday, December 20th!!
スタートデッキ3種も同時発売！！
Three starter decks releasing simultaneously!!
公式アプリ「ホロプラス」の魅力を聞いてみた！
We asked about the appeal of the official app "Holoplus"!
「マイ推し」の最新情報が通知される！
Get notifications for your oshi's latest updates!
「ホロジュール」がすぐ開けるので配信を見逃さない！
Open "Holojue" instantly so you never miss a stream!
色々な地域の仲間とコメントやいいねで共感できるあったかい空間！
A warm space where you can connect with fans everywhere through comments and likes!
あなたのコメントが企画に！？公式番組「ホロの休日（仮）」
Your comments become projects!? Official show "Hololive Holiday (Tentative)"
販売終了間近のグッズが分かる！グッズ情報案内板などなど！
Know when merch is ending sales! Goods info board and more!
うわ〜！他にもこんなにたくさん〜すごい！
Wow~! There's so much more—amazing!
是非あなたのホロ活にプラスしませんか？ここからインストールできます！
Why not add it to your hololife? You can install it right here!
ホロプラスで待ってますね！
We'll be waiting for you on Holoplus!
はあちゃま、はい！
Haachama, here!
ん？
Hm?
急に何？
What's this all of a sudden?
いいからいいから！
Just take it!
普通に美味しい！
It's actually delicious!
ちょっと形が崩れただけだもん 落ち込むことないよ
Its shape just got a little messed up, nothing to be down about.
はあちゃまが頑張ってくれたの知ってるから ちょっとずつ一緒に覚えていこうよ、ね？
I know how hard you tried, so let's learn together step by step, okay?
うん？
Hm?
それじゃあ 次コロッケ作る時はオリジナルのレシピを考えておくわ きっともっと美味しくなるわよ！
Then next time we make croquettes, I'll come up with an original recipe. I'm sure it'll be even more delicious!
やだ
No way.
なんでよ！はあちゃまならもっとおいしく…
Why not! If it's Haachama, it'll be even more delicious...
やだ
No way!
はあちゃまならもっとおいしく…
Hachama would make it even tastier...
ダメ
No.
異世界ドタバタクッキングコメディ！
An otherworldly slapstick cooking comedy!
ホロアースデイズ あ・た・る・せ・い・ど・た・ぶ・り・ゅー
Holoearth Days: A Tail Side W
ウェスタdeクッキング 幸上のルセット
Westa de Cooking: Recipe of Happiness
大好評連載中！
Now heavily serialized!
個性の光が色彩となり 響き合う。
The light of individuality becomes color, resonating together.
私たちのステージは、今、鮮やかに色づきはじめる。
Our stage now begins to color vibrantly.
ホロライブ史上最大の幕張メッセ 国際展示場9-11ホールを使った大規模fes.
The largest-ever Hololive festival, utilizing Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Halls 9-11.
多くのクリエイターが生み出した名曲の数々を、多彩なホロライブメンバーたちの表現力で再び披露する特別なステージ。
A special stage where numerous masterpieces created by many creators are performed once again through the expressive power of various Hololive members.
さあ、心を響かせ、あなたの色をこのハーモニーに加えてください。
Now, let your heart resonate and add your color to this harmony.